Parwinder Kaur DinabandhuNiwas Joydutta Press, Near Uruli's Lalganesh Guwahati – 781034 Cell - 9864201216; 9864049869 Email: pariikaur68@gmail.com



# **PROFILE:**

A creative and resourceful teacher to enhance student performance offering 20+years of experience with varied instructional methods and ICT (Information & Communications Technology) skills. Believe in training minds to think and climb their own mountains. Currently working as a Freelance Linguist for translations, transcriptions, AI data voices, voice over(remote), subtitle editing, second proofreading, gaming localization translation with leading NGOs and agencies like – Translators without Borders, COP26 Coalition team, Teemwork.ai Corporation, Linguatistics.com, OneForma by Centific, ProZ.com, Trident Language Services.com, MultiBhashi.com, etc. since October'21, nationally and internationally.

Highly ambitious and committed to assigned tasks as a proactive team leader with inter-personal skills to serve organizational goals or targets. As one of the International Coordinators in 2014, participated and accredited South Point School Guwahati with their first INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL AWARD (2014-2017) by the British Council for collaborative and curriculum based international projects-'CONNECTING CLASSROOMS' involving and partnering global school community. Under the Teachers Exchange Program, was invited at Crook Primary School, Durham, England (to exchange the culture of India, especially the North East) and as guests at St. Cuthbert's RC Primary School Durham, England in 2014.

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS:**

- B.Ed under Gauhati University in 2002-03 (College of Education, Boko)
- B.A under Gauhati University in 1990 (Handique Girls' College, Guwahati)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

- Currently a freelancer for Voice over(IVR- English, Hindi, Punjabi) for Multibhashi.com;
   Translation( English> < Hindi, Punjabi> English/Hindi), Subtitling (English/Hindi/Punjabi),
   Transcription (English>Punjabi/Hindi), Text Alignment (AI) with Trident Translation Services;
   Annotation and Voice Data collection with OneForma by Centific; Audio Data for Voice recognition model (AI) and NLP(Natural Language Processing) with Linguatistic.com, etc.
- Freelancing as a Linguist (Translation, Reviewing, Transcription, Audio QA, etc for Eng>
   Hindi/Punjabi) with leading NGOs Translators without Borders, COP26 Coalition team and other
   reputed agencies since October 2021
- Worked at Delhi Public School (CBSE) Khanapara, Meghalaya as TGT English from 11 March 2015 to 31 November 2019
- Worked at South Point School (CBSE), Guwahati as an Upper Primary Teacher(PRT) English from Aug 2007 to November 2014
- Worked at St. Clare's Convent High School (SEBA), Guwahati as an Assistant Teacher for English (Secondary School) from 03 Aug 2006 to 29 March 2007
- Worked at Assam Institute of Computer Studies; Guwahati as a Spoken English Instructor (Part time) from 2001 to 2002
- Worked at Guru Gobind Singh Public School (CBSE), Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand as a Junior Teacher for English (Secondary School) from 01 Jan 1997 to 31 Mar 1999
- Worked at Shishu Niketan English High School (SEBA), Guwahati as an Assistant Teacher for English and S.St (Middle School) from 22 Mar 1991 to 31 Aug 1992

• Worked at St. Mary's Convent School Maligaon, Guwahati as an Assistant Teacher against leave vacancy (PrimarySchool) from 08 Oct 1990 to 28 Dec 1990

### **WORK PROFILE:**

- Ongoing successful projects as Freelancer Voice-Over for Hindi and English (IVR) for reputed apps and NGOs with Multibhashi.com.
- Worked as Translator/Annotator for English> Hindi/Punjabi (bilingual) via OneForma by Centific and Audio Data Recorder in Punjabi and Hindi language for machine -learning used in Voice Recognition Model and NLP (Natural Language Processing) for Linguatistic.com
- Responsibly worked as a freelancer for Speech Data collection in Teemwork.ai Corporation in Hindi Language for AI for US clients
- Achieved Translation appraisal from Translators Without Borders and Certificate from COP26'
  Coalition
- Took charge of translation reviewing and Audio QA checks with NGOs and other international agencies
- Coordinated and shouldered the day-to-day responsibilities of planning and executing Scholastic and Co-Scholastic Events and Activities, Assembly, Teacher Substitution Arrangements
- Coordinated and managed Exam Cell
- Co-in-charge of systems for school assessments and development -Entab and Fedena
- Coordinated teachers' queries in handling the Snap Homework App
- Headed as the House Warden
- Conducted, managed, recorded the data and compiled entire report of COMMON REVISION ASSESSMENT and QUALITY ASSESSMENT PROGRAMME organized by THE DPSS- DELHI
- In- charge of English department
- International Coordinator for INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL AWARD (BRITISH COUNCIL) and conducted international projects in collaboration with UK INDIA EDUCATION AND RESEARCH INITIATIVE@ British Council
- Managed ALL INDIA KOREA-INDIA FRIENDSHIP ESSAY COMPETITION '19(KOREAN CULTURE CENTRE, EMBASSY OF REPUBLIC OF KOREA)
- Conducted, managed and recorded CBSE instituted SWACHHA BHARAT MISSION and Environmental Missions in and around the school to instill moral values and self- awareness in students, teachers and the neighbouring community, along with the report submission
- Assisted in organizing MOCK UNITED NATIONS event and workshops on Anti-Tobacco, Adolescence issues etc. by parents as Resource Persons
- Coordinated extra-curricular activities SPELL BEE INDIA, NATIONAL SCIENCE OLYMPIAD(ENGLISH), ASSET INDIA (Educational Initiatives), SCHOLASTICS INDIA and Inter School literary activities/ competitions
- Anchored and staged programmes based on national and regional festivals, and commemorative days
- Assisted by giving prompts and direction in group activities in staging plays, recitations, etc. on annual functions and special days
- Scripted and prepared student anchors, Management speeches, and supervised the Annual Day Function(back stage, on stage, catering, discipline, etc)
- Sub-Editor of the school magazines
- Helped in planning and organizing Parent-Teacher Meetings
- Assisted the Headmistress in planning the academic calendar, making formats of lesson plan, maintaining Chapter Distribution Records of teachers and compiling Subject Reports
- Acted as a liaison between the teachers and the head to conduct all events and activities, and record academic data

- Planned with teacher teams, organized, and implemented age-appropriate program activities
- Maintained and record details of all school events, activities and workshops related to student and teachers for preparation of School AnnualReport
- Encouraged teacher participation through resources, instructed and supervised the execution of their responsible event or group activity
- Responsible for teachers' syllabus planning, preparations and timely completion, ensuring conduction of assignments in due time
- An active part of teacher recruit team, served as a coach to newly hired teachers and conduct induction/ orientation programs to understand and make comfortable in a new environment
- Responsible for maintaining discipline in required areas
- Handled the communication between administrative staff and the teachers
- Conducted mock drills for preparedness of a natural disaster(Earthquake) under Disaster Management Act

# CERTIFICATION, PROJECTS AND WORKSHOPS ATTENDED ON:

- Translation certificates from Translators without borders, COP'26 Coalition, OneForma
- Workshops attended on school assessment and development systems Entab and Fedena
- TEACHNEXT systems workshop for school curriculum and execution of academics
- SNAPHOMEWORK workshop ( a class assessment app)
- WEBINAR ENGLISH EDGE SCHOLAR training for assessment for speaking and listening for Language Lab (ONLINE MEETINGS AND CONFERENCING)
- Achieved INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL AWARD-'CONNECTING CLASSROOMS' project Class 1 to 9 IN 2013-2014 as BRITISH COUNCIL INTERNATIONAL COORDINATOR in South Point School, Guwahati
- Visited UK and participated in BRITISH COUNCIL'S CONNECTING CLASSROOMS PROJECT at CrookPrimary School and St. Cuthbert's Roman Catholic Primary School, Durham, UK in October 2014(www.crookprimary.org.uk)
- International School Award on 'LOOKING GOOD' with Class 4 (British Council's Connecting Classrooms) linking with UK and USA in 2014
- Project Brazil 'KIDS IN THE KITCHEN with Class 3,4 and5; 'Festivals of India' and 'Flags around the World' with Class 6 and 7 (United Kingdom India Education and Research Initiative @ BRITISHCOUNCIL)
- Certificate in LEARNING ONLINE WITH CONNECTING CLASSROOMS for teachers (Schools Online @BRITISH COUNCILS' ONLINE PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT COURSE)
- Certificate SHAKESPEAREAN DRAMA WORKSHOP(ROYAL SHAKESPEARE COMPANY,UK) under the guidance of Ms. Barbara Gentles and Ms. Anna Bowden from CROOK PRIMARY SCHOOL,DURHAM,UK
- 'Skills for Adolescence' (Ohio, USA) and Skills for Growing' sponsored by LIONS QUEST IN INDIA FOUNDATION
- English workshops attended Madhuban Publications for 'English Creative Skills', Macmillan Publications, Orient Blackswan Publications
- SQL 8.0 and COMPUTER APPLICATIONS, Assam Institute of Computer Science, Guwahati
- Certificate in JOURNALISM. Institute of Journalism. New Delhi
- Diploma in PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT & IND. RELATIONS, All India Instituteof Management Studies, Chennai

I hereby declare that the above furnished particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

**Parwinder Kaur**